Talk to Sahaja Yogis from Africa Swiss Hotel, Istanbul, 23.04.2001
Afrika’dan gelen Sahaja Yogilerle Konuşma, Swiss Hotel, İstanbul, 23.04.2001
This should not come (happen) to you people because
Bu sizin başınıza gelmemeli çünkü
you live with the nature and nature is not , nature is never corrupt.
siz doğanın içinde yaşıyorsunuz, tabiat böyle değildir, doğa asla yozlaşmaz.
You know, every leaf, you will be amazed
Biliyorsunuz, her bir yaprak, buna hayret edersiniz,
which is on the tree, every leaf , gets the sunshine.
meydana getirilen her yaprak güneş ışığını alır
Every leaf is different in the world, every leaf
Dünyadaki her yaprak farklıdır, her bir yaprak.
and the way they organize is in such a manner,
Ve onların organize olma şekillleri de öyledir,
that all of them get the sunslight.
hepsi gün ışığını alırlar.
But in corruption, one wants to have all  everything
Ancak yozlaşmada, kişi her şeye sahip olmak ister.
You have...
sahip olmak
And then,
Ve o zaman da,
he doesn't know what is the joy in giving to others.
başkalarına vermenin neşesini bilmezler.
You see, that’s how it happens with Sahaja Yoga that
Bakın, Sahaja Yoga içinde son derece
you become extremely generous.
cömert olmak işte böyle oluyor.
I’ll give the example of my husband
Kocamdan örnek vereceğim
or I should say of my father.
ya da Babam demeliyim.
He was a very, very generous man, very.
O çok, çok cömert birisiydi, çok.
And he told us not to lock the house.
ve bize kapıyı kilitlememizi söylerdi,
Keep it open, no thief will come.
açık bırakın, eve hırsız girmeyecektir derdi.
But one night a thief came and he took away
Ama bir gece, eve hırsız girdi ve bu büyük
this big gramophone which had this big horn,
borusu olan, eski bir büyük gramofonu
and he took off.
alıp götürdü.
And  the second day, my husband, my father was got upset.
ve ertesi gün Babam üzgündü.
He was little bit  upset.
Biraz üzgündü.
So my mother said: “Is it because of the gramophone?”,
Bunun üzerine Annem: “Gramofon yüzünden mi?”,
“Is it because of the gramophone, you are upset?”
“Gramofon yüzünden mi üzgünsün?” dedi.
He said, “No, we can buy
O da, “Hayır, gramofon satın alabiliriz
but what about this man, he has taken  no records, what will  he use?”
ama bu adamın plakları almamış olmasına ne demeli, neyi dinleyecek şimdi?” dedi.
My mother said, “Alright.”
Annem de, “Tamam”, dedi.
And he said, “He should have brought somebody else to take the gramophone.”
Ve devam etti, “Gramafonu götürmek için başka birini daha getirmeliydi.”
So my mother said “Alright”,
Bu durumda Annem “Peki,
“What should we advertise in the newspaper?
bu durumda gazetede nasıl bir duyuru yapmalıyız?
One who has stolen the gramophone can also take away the records.”
Gramofonu çalan kişi, buraya gelip plakları da alabilir.”
That kind of generosity it is, that kind.
Bu tür bir cömertlik, bu türden.
He said, we can afford to buy  both, the poor man is organiser of music,
Babam, ikisini de alabileceğimizi söyledi.
Very generous, extremely generous.
Çok cömertti, son derece cömert.
So, you see, the generosity is the only way we can correct corruption.
Yani, bakın, yozlaşmayı düzeltebilmemizin tek yolu, cömerttliktir.
When you start enjoying giving, you don’t grab.
Vermekten neşe duymaya başladığınız zaman, siz gasp etmezsiniz.
And such a person has no reputation in the society
Ve böyle bir kişinin toplum içinde bir itibarı yoktur
and that money that his  grabs, is of no use.
ve gasp ettiği paranın da hiçbir yararı yoktur.
And all those people who have made money like that,
Ve bu şekilde para kazanan tüm insanlar,
have lost it when they put in this Swiss Bank.
bu parayı İsviçre Bankasına yatırdıkları zaman, kaybetmişlerdir.
And the swiss bank also does not away loaf it.
Ve İsviçre bankası da onu boşa çıkarmaz.
They can give so much good but they don’t,
Onlar çok iyi şeyler verebilirler ama vermezler,
they are keeping  the money, they are sitting on top.
bütün parayı saklıyor ve tepesinde oturuyorlar.
So one has to, if say anything you should  talk about the Swiss bank.
Yani, bir şey söyleyecek olursanız, İsviçre bankası hakkında konuşmanız gerekir.
Stop the Swiss bank. It’s cheating, complete cheating.
İsviçre bankasını durdurun. Bu kandırmaktır, bu tam bir dalaveredir.
I don’t know how they are legalized,
Bunu nasıl yasallaştırıldıklarını bilmiyorum,
they take money from the thieves and keep it there.
hırsızlardan parayı alıyor ve orada muhafaza ediyorlar.
How can they do that?
Bunu nasıl yapabilirler?
If you stop the working of the Swiss bank,
Eğer İsviçre Bankasını durdurursanız,
I telll you the corruption will go away.
söylemeliyim, yolsuzluk ortadan kalkacaktır.
That’s the only way you can stop this high-class corruption.
Bu üst sınıf yolsuzluğu durdurmanın tek yolu budur.
You should write, you should write about it.
Yazmalısınız, bununların hepsini yazmalısınız
Americans are very careful.
Amerikalılar çok dikkatlidir.
If you send any money from America to Switzerland,
Eğer siz Amerika’dan İsviçre’ye bir para gönderirseniz,
Switzerland informs they are in legalize.
İsviçre yasallaştırıldıklarını bildirir.
There was  in Brazil you see
Orada Brezilya’da
I met  the minister of law and also
hukuk ve adalet bakanıyla
justice, chief justice, both of them I met.
ve baş yargıçla, onların her ikisiyle de görüştüm.
They were very respectful
Onlar çok saygılıydılar
but they said that in our country we had a prime minister who was  impeached.
fakat dediler ki, ülkemizde, suçlanan bir  başbakanımız vardı.
impeached.
suçlandı.
And that fellow has God now a very great job
Ve bu adam şimdi iyi bir işe ...
in the University of whatever say that ...
üniversite, neydi adı...
Switzerland.
İsviçre...
No, no, no , in the America
Hayır, hayır Amerika'da
Harvard, Harvard University;but  teaching Economic  [UNCLEAR].
Harvard Üniversitesi’nde çok iyi bir işe sahip; ekonomi öğretiyor
He was impeached.
Kendisin suçlanmıştı
All kinds of  thieves will be now going to these bigger universities,
Her tür hırsız artık bu  büyük üniversitelere gidecek.
and they will teach our children how to cheat.
ve çocuklarımıza nasıl hile yapılacağını öğretecekler.
That’s what it  is coming.
İşte gelmekte olan şey bu.
I spoke about it in China, when  they had this women conference that called.
Kadın konferansı sırasında Çin’de, bunun hakkında konuştum.
But I don’t know, this is a big game going on.
Ama bilemiyorum, bu devam etmekte olan büyük bir oyun
It’s a thing to be seen from Sahaja.
Ve bu Sahaja’dan görülecek bir şey.
If we don't workout, I'm sure will be better it
Eğer bir şey yapmazsak, eminim her şey daha iyi olacak.
Because it’s a woman global work, global.
Çünkü küresel bir kadın işi, küresel.
So, it can not fail.
Yani başarısız olamaz.
Because  the power of the collective.
Çünkü kollektivitenin gücü.
I wish you could have a conference one day,
Keşke hepinizle Hindistan’da veya
of  all these people  in India or may be new country.
yeni başka bir ülkede, bir gün bir konferans düzenleyebilsek.
Guido: Yes Shri Mataji
Guido:Evet, Shri Mataji
You should go once and a new  big conference there.
Bir kez gitmeli ve orada  bir büyük konferans yapmalısınız.